[
 {
  "QUESTION": "1. Educational stakeholders are considered more important to a school when they;",
  "answer1": "A. Use their power in support of the school",
  "answer2": "B. raise legitimate issues about teaching",
  "answer3": "C. express themselves eloquently",
  "answer4": "D. emphasize the urgency of their issues",
  "correctanswer": "A. Use their power in support of the school"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "2. Which of the following are the main priorities of the Ghana Education Reform Agenda? I. Improved learning outcomes II. Enhanced accountability III. Equality IV. Equity",
  "answer1": "A. II, III, and IV only",
  "answer2": "B. I, II, III and IV only",
  "answer3": "C. I, II, and IV only",
  "answer4": "D. I, II, and III only",
  "correctanswer": "C. I, II, and IV only"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "3. What is the purpose of conducting research?",
  "answer1": "A. To provide solutions to problems",
  "answer2": "B. To identify a problem needing solution",
  "answer3": "C. To add to knowledge",
  "answer4": "D. All of the above",
  "correctanswer": "D. All of the above"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "4. In which year was the Pre-tertiary Education Act (Act 1049) enacted?",
  "answer1": "A. 2020",
  "answer2": "B. 2008",
  "answer3": "C. 1987",
  "answer4": "D. 1961",
  "correctanswer": "A. 2020"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "5. Which of the following key qualities are required of a public officer? I. Leadership skills II. Communication skills III. Patience and resilience",
  "answer1": "A. II only",
  "answer2": "B. II and III only",
  "answer3": "C. I, II, and III only",
  "answer4": "D. I and II only",
  "correctanswer": "C. I, II, and III only"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "6. The degree to which a person identifies with his or her job, actively participates in it, and considers his or her performance as being important to self-worth is referred to as job",
  "answer1": "A. stability",
  "answer2": "B. satisfaction",
  "answer3": "C. involvement",
  "answer4": "D. commitment",
  "correctanswer": "B. satisfaction"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "Use the Scenario below to answer questions 7 and 8. Ama works as a receptionist at an educational institution. Her boss just came through the door and yelled at her, telling her that the front office was a mess and that she needed to get up and clean it immediately. After her boss left the room, Ama grabbed some new papers and violently slammed them into the dustbin."
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "7. Which of the following best describes Ama's action?",
  "answer1": "A. A mood",
  "answer2": "B. A thought",
  "answer3": "C. An effect",
  "answer4": "D. An emotion",
  "correctanswer": "D. An emotion"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "8. Which of the following best describes the behaviour of Ama's boss?",
  "answer1": "A. Authoritarian",
  "answer2": "B. Disrespectful",
  "answer3": "C. Impolite",
  "answer4": "D. Rude",
  "correctanswer": "D. Rude"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "9. When decision making is delegated as far down the chain of command as possible in an education system, the system is said to be",
  "answer1": "A. centralised.",
  "answer2": "B. creative.",
  "answer3": "C. decentralised.",
  "answer4": "D. flexible.",
  "correctanswer": "C. decentralised."
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "10. Which of the following is not a characteristic of well-constructed goal of educational organisations? They",
  "answer1": "A. address critical issues",
  "answer2": "B. are challenging but realistic",
  "answer3": "C. are precise and measurable.",
  "answer4": "D. are the result of a group decision process.",
  "correctanswer": "D. are the result of a group decision process."
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "11. The district director of education's office phone bill in 2020 is GHC4,200.00. It increases by 10% in 2021, and a further 20% increase in the first six months of 2022. If the Director settles the 2020 bill, how much more will she have to pay at the end of June 2022?",
  "answer1": "A. GHC 4,400.00",
  "answer2": "B. GHC 4,620.00",
  "answer3": "C. GHC 5,544.00",
  "answer4": "D. GHC 5,744.00",
  "correctanswer": "C. GHC 5,544.00"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "12. Which Act established the Complementary Education Agency (CEA)?",
  "answer1": "A. 2020 (Act 1023)",
  "answer2": "B. 2020 (Act 1049)",
  "answer3": "C. 2020 (Act 1055)",
  "answer4": "D. 2020 (Act 1058)",
  "correctanswer": "C. 2020 (Act 1055)"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "13. Which of the following is not a key education reform area of the ministry of education",
  "answer1": "A. Pre-Tertiary Curriculum Reform through NaCCA",
  "answer2": "B. Policy on Teacher Education Reforms led by GTEC through T-TEL",
  "answer3": "C. Global Citizenship Education Reform",
  "answer4": "D. GES Institutional and Human Resource Reform",
  "correctanswer": "C. Global Citizenship Education Reform"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "14. What is the following fallacy called? \"All ducks love water. Kofi loves water. Therefore, Kofi is a duck.\"",
  "answer1": "A. Modus tollens",
  "answer2": "B. Modus ponens",
  "answer3": "C. Denying the antecedent",
  "answer4": "D. Affirming; the consequent",
  "correctanswer": "D. Affirming; the consequent"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "15. The best approach for transformational change in a school is to have the school leader create an atmosphere for change",
  "answer1": "A. but let others decide how to initiate change.",
  "answer2": "B. but carefully set limits for the program.",
  "answer3": "C. and establish a reward system.",
  "answer4": "D. and begin establishing a vision.",
  "correctanswer": "D. and begin establishing a vision."
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "16. Which one of the following best describes the focus of inclusive education? To increase",
  "answer1": "A. participation of all students in schools including those with disabilities.",
  "answer2": "B. participation of all staff in decision making including non-teaching staff.",
  "answer3": "C. integration of various subject disciplines such as arts, science and business.",
  "answer4": "D. integration of basic secondary and tertiary systems of education.",
  "correctanswer": "A. participation of all students in schools including those with disabilities."
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "17. The principal strategy adopted for Universal Design for Learning (UDL) is",
  "answer1": "A. inviting parents to attend school meetings and open days.",
  "answer2": "B. giving learners quizzes at the end of every lesson.",
  "answer3": "C. asking parents to sign the completed assignments of learners.",
  "answer4": "D. adopting multiple ways of representing content to learners.",
  "correctanswer": "D. adopting multiple ways of representing content to learners."
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "18. Which of the following is not one of the four pillars of secondary education reform in Ghana?",
  "answer1": "A. Promote skill development and equity",
  "answer2": "B. Improve equality.",
  "answer3": "C. Expand physical infrastructure",
  "answer4": "D. Absorb all fees paid",
  "correctanswer": "B. Improve equality."
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "19. Who is the Director-General of the Ghana TVET Service?",
  "answer1": "A. Mr David-Prah",
  "answer2": "B. Madam Mawusi Nudekor Awity",
  "answer3": "C. Madam Gifty Twum-Ampofo",
  "answer4": "D. Dr. Fred Kyei Asamoah",
  "correctanswer": "B. Madam Mawusi Nudekor Awity"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "20. The plans of school management are often expressed formally in which of the following documents?",
  "answer1": "A. Performance reports",
  "answer2": "B. Ledgers",
  "answer3": "C. Financial statements.",
  "answer4": "D. Budgets",
  "correctanswer": "D. Budgets"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "21. In an educational institution, the idolisation of a charismatic leader by followers can lead to",
  "answer1": "A. difficulty in developing a successor.",
  "answer2": "B. greater understanding of the organisation mission",
  "answer3": "C. limiting suggestions of fixes and improvements.",
  "answer4": "D. nurtures a competitive work environment.\n",
  "correctanswer": "A. difficulty in developing a successor."
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "22. In educational settings, since practical considerations make job try-outs for all candidates impracticable, it is necessary to……………… the relative level of job performance for each candidate on the basis of available information.",
  "answer1": "A. Abandon",
  "answer2": "B. Accept",
  "answer3": "C. Assign",
  "answer4": "D. Predict",
  "correctanswer": "D. Predict"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "23. Which one of the following cognitive biases refer to the fact that educational decision makers who have strong prior beliefs about an issue tend to make decisions on the basis of these beliefs, even when presented with evidence that their beliefs are wrong?",
  "answer1": "A. Escalating commitment bias",
  "answer2": "B. Illusion control bias",
  "answer3": "C. Prior hypothesis bias",
  "answer4": "D. Reasoning by analogy bias",
  "correctanswer": "C. Prior hypothesis bias"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "24. An important first step in the process of formulating an educational institution's mission is to",
  "answer1": "A. answer the question, \"What is our business?\"",
  "answer2": "B. decide what the Institution will be like 10 years from now.",
  "answer3": "C. evaluate the institution's most recent performance.",
  "answer4": "D. identify the client segment served by the nstitution.\n",
  "correctanswer": "A. answer the question, \"What is our business?\""
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "25. A headmistress wanted her school to keep costs low. Therefore, as an example to others, she drove her own car to school and furnished her office with plain, steel desk. In this case, the headmistress was displaying her",
  "answer1": "A. astute use of power.",
  "answer2": "B. commitment to her cause.",
  "answer3": "C emotional intelligence.",
  "answer4": "D. vision for success.",
  "correctanswer": "B. commitment to her cause."
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "26. An argument is sure to be a sound argument if it is a\/an",
  "answer1": "A. argument which is completely valid.",
  "answer2": "B. argument with a true conclusion",
  "answer3": "C. argument with true premises.",
  "answer4": "D. guarantee of the truth of its conclusion.",
  "correctanswer": "A. argument which is completely valid."
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "27. Teachers could be made to be more accountable when they are given the",
  "answer1": "A freedom to select content and methods of teaching.",
  "answer2": "B. opportunity for professional growth.",
  "answer3": "C. option to transfer to places where they want to serve",
  "answer4": "D. training in teaching and examining",
  "correctanswer": "A freedom to select content and methods of teaching."
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "Use the information below to answer questions 28 to 30. The administration of a senior high school wants to know what proportion of their students are satisfied with the library facilities. Eighteen (18) library staff are keen to help. They select 200 students in the library during the first week of exam period and ask them to fill in a questionnaire on satisfaction with the library."
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "28. What is the population that the sample was selected from?",
  "answer1": "A. The 200 students who completed the questionnaire.",
  "answer2": "B. All students in the library during the first week of the exam period.",
  "answer3": "C. All the senior high school students.",
  "answer4": "D. All the students and library staff.",
  "correctanswer": "B. All students in the library during the first week of the exam period."
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "29. In the survey conducted by the library staff at the senior high school, what is the population that the school administration is interested in?",
  "answer1": "A. The 200 students who completed the questionnaire.",
  "answer2": "B. All students enrolled at the senior high school.",
  "answer3": "C. All students in the library during the first week of the exam period",
  "answer4": "D. All the students and library staff.",
  "correctanswer": "B. All students enrolled at the senior high school."
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "30. What is the sample size for this survey?",
  "answer1": "A 200",
  "answer2": 8.205,
  "answer3": "C.218",
  "answer4": "D.220",
  "correctanswer": "A 200"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "31. Who won the Best Teacher (Leadership and Administration) in the 2022 Ghana Teacher Prize?",
  "answer1": "A. Madam Ivy Asantewaa Owusu",
  "answer2": "B. Madam Stella Gyimaah Larbi",
  "answer3": "C. Mr. Joseph Kwaku Agbevanu",
  "answer4": "D. Mr. McClean Owusu-Boateng",
  "correctanswer": "A. Madam Ivy Asantewaa Owusu"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "32. In a learner-centred school, the head teacher undertakes all the following activities to enhance teaching and learning except",
  "answer1": "A. empowering teachers to involve each learner in the teaching\/learning process.",
  "answer2": "B. encouraging teachers to avoid tests because they demoralize students.",
  "answer3": "C. encouraging teachers to develop lesson plans that build on existing knowledge.",
  "answer4": "D. motivating and sustaining teachers' interest in teaching.B. encouraging teachers to avoid tests because they demoralize students."
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "33. The general competence intended by Ghana's pre-tertiary education curriculum framework to promote entrepreneurial skills in learners is",
  "answer1": "A. communication and collaboration.",
  "answer2": "B. creativity and innovation.",
  "answer3": "C. critical thinking and problem solving.",
  "answer4": "D. personal development and leadership.",
  "correctanswer": "B. Creativity and innovation"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "34. The type of test that measures the performance of learners against the standard covered in the curriculum is called a\/an",
  "answer1": "A. aptitude test",
  "answer2": "B. criterion-referenced test",
  "answer3": "C. diagnostic test.",
  "answer4": "D. norm-referenced test.",
  "correctanswer": "C. diagnostic test."
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "35. Which of the following is not one of the core domains of the national teachers’ standards? Professional",
  "answer1": "A. ethics",
  "answer2": "B. knowledge.",
  "answer3": "C. practice.",
  "answer4": "D. values and attitudes",
  "correctanswer": "A. ethics"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "36. Which of the following is not a tool for formative assessment in the school system?",
  "answer1": "A. Inventory",
  "answer2": "B. Multiple Choice Question",
  "answer3": "C. Oral Questions",
  "answer4": "D. Projects",
  "correctanswer": "A. Inventory"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "37. Which of the following relates to the affective domain of students' behaviour?",
  "answer1": "A. Attitudes",
  "answer2": "B. Feelings",
  "answer3": "C. Stereotypes",
  "answer4": "D. All of the above",
  "correctanswer": "D. All of the above"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "38. The topmost responsibility of a head teacher is to",
  "answer1": "A. provide leadership for learning.",
  "answer2": "B. maintain school records.",
  "answer3": "C. handle discipline problems.",
  "answer4": "D. administer the guidance programme.",
  "correctanswer": "A. provide leadership for learning."
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "39. The first important step in teaching is",
  "answer1": "A. planning beforehand.",
  "answer2": "B. organizing material to be taught.",
  "answer3": "C. knowing the background of the students.",
  "answer4": "D. writing questions for diagnostic assessment.",
  "correctanswer": "C. knowing the background of the students."
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "40. In what year did GES replace promotion interviews with promotion examinations?",
  "answer1": "A. 2017",
  "answer2": "B. 2018",
  "answer3": "C. 2019",
  "answer4": "D. 2020",
  "correctanswer": "D. 2020"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "41. The main objective of classroom assessment is to",
  "answer1": "A. compare learners' performance.",
  "answer2": "B. measure teachers' effectiveness.",
  "answer3": "C. report on learners' performance to parents.",
  "answer4": "D. Improve teaching and learning",
  "correctanswer": "D. Improve teaching and learning"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "42. A teacher teaches in a remote school where newspapers are delivered irregularly with the importance of keeping the students abreast with current affairs in mind, what is the best way to keep the students updated?",
  "answer1": "A. Urge the pupils to listen to stories circulating in the community",
  "answer2": "B. Try all available means to get the newspaper delivered to the school",
  "answer3": "C. Gather back issues of newspapers and let pupils compile them.",
  "answer4": "D. Encourage the pupils to listen to the daily broadcasts from a radio",
  "correctanswer": "D. Encourage the pupils to listen to the daily broadcasts from a radio"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "43. Learners are most likely to be intrinsically motivated to learn and master subject matter when they",
  "answer1": "A. perceive that their performance will compare favourably with that of peers.",
  "answer2": "B. know they will receive positive reinforcement for achieving instructional objectives.",
  "answer3": "C. know they will be tested on their understanding of the content in the near future.",
  "answer4": "D. believe that the work they are doing is interesting and relates to their own lives.",
  "correctanswer": "D. believe that the work they are doing is interesting and relates to their own lives."
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "44. The fundamental aim of supervision is to help",
  "answer1": "A. teachers in understanding pupils.",
  "answer2": "B. teachers in improving methods.",
  "answer3": "C. teachers in dealing with pupils.",
  "answer4": "D. children learn more effectively.",
  "correctanswer": "D. children learn more effectively"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "45. To make learning effective, an instructional goal must be meaningful in terms of",
  "answer1": "A. students' needs and purposes.",
  "answer2": "B. standards of others.",
  "answer3": "C. objectives of the curriculum.",
  "answer4": "D. intellectual ideas.",
  "correctanswer": "A. students' needs and purposes."
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "46. Procedures used to determine a learner's abilities are referred to as",
  "answer1": "A. typical performance test.",
  "answer2": "B. norm-referenced test.",
  "answer3": "C. maximum performance test.",
  "answer4": "D. criterion-referenced test.",
  "correctanswer": "C. maximum performance test."
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "47. What are the three components of an educational process?",
  "answer1": "A. Teaching, learning and practice",
  "answer2": "B. Teacher, student and education",
  "answer3": "C. Education, teacher and books",
  "answer4": "D. Direction, instruction and skill",
  "correctanswer": "B. Teacher, student and education"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "48. Which one of the following does not characterise a well-planned lesson?",
  "answer1": "A. Varied teaching and learning resources are utilised to promote learning",
  "answer2": "B. Varied procedures and activities are undertaken by the pupils",
  "answer3": "C. Lesson objectives are specific, measurable, and achievable",
  "answer4": "D. Lesson notes are vetted by school head",
  "correctanswer": "D. Lesson notes are vetted by school head"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "49. The capitation grant provided to a school can be used for the following purposes except to",
  "answer1": "A. procure stationery for the school.",
  "answer2": "B. organise extra classes for pupils.",
  "answer3": "C. attend to sanitation and minor repairs and maintenance.",
  "answer4": "D. acquire teaching and learning resources.",
  "correctanswer": "B. organise extra classes for pupils."
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "50. What is the most important factor a teacher should consider in selecting and utilising instructional materials?",
  "answer1": "A. Objectives of the lesson",
  "answer2": "B. Degree of interest on the part of the studentsC. Availability of instructional materials",
  "answer4": "D. Attractiveness of instructional material",
  "correctanswer": "A. Objectives of the lesson"
 },
 {
  "correctanswer": "section b"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "51.In any school situation, performance tasks are hands on activities that require students to demonstrate their ability to perform certain actions.",
  "answer1": "A. False",
  "answer2": "B. True",
  "correctanswer": "B. True"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "52. The final outcome of successful strategic competitiveness is above-average returns.",
  "answer1": "A. False",
  "answer2": "B. True",
  "correctanswer": "A. False"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "53. Teachers who are respected and liked are associated with greater student satisfaction and higher achievement.",
  "answer1": "A. False",
  "answer2": "B. True",
  "correctanswer": "B. True"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "54. Monitoring involves the development of a forecast of what might happen at a future point in time.",
  "answer1": "A. False",
  "answer2": "B. True",
  "correctanswer": "A. False"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "55. A teacher cannot exhibit referent power from the first day of class by giving students a sense of belonging and acceptance.",
  "answer1": "A. False",
  "answer2": "B. True",
  "correctanswer": "A. False"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "56. Since the health of a nations' economy affects the performance of individual firms and industries, organisations study the economic environment to identify changes, trends, and their strategic implications.",
  "answer1": "A. False",
  "answer2": "B. True",
  "correctanswer": "B. True"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "57. Licensure and exit tests are the best predictors of classroom performance of teachers.",
  "answer1": "A. False",
  "answer2": "B. True",
  "correctanswer": "B. True"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "58. External environmental analysis should be conducted annually.",
  "answer1": "A. False",
  "answer2": "B. True",
  "correctanswer": "A. False"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "59. If a person teaches with a high degree of clarity, he\/she will spend less time going over material.",
  "answer1": "A. False",
  "answer2": "B. True",
  "correctanswer": "B. True"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "60. Student performance is higher in classes where the teacher devotes large amount of time to materials rather than teaching content",
  "answer1": "A. False",
  "answer2": "B. True",
  "correctanswer": "A. False"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "61. In Ghana, the National Teachers' Standard is the maximum levels of practice that all trained teachers must reach by the end of their pre-service teacher education course in order to play such a critical role.",
  "answer1": "A. False",
  "answer2": "B. True",
  "correctanswer": "A. False"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "62. The purpose of evaluating learning is to make a Judgement about the quality of education provided.",
  "answer1": "A. False",
  "answer2": "B. True",
  "correctanswer": "B. True"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "63. Measurement is the quantitative assessment of performance of learners.",
  "answer1": "A. False",
  "answer2": "B. True",
  "correctanswer": "B. True"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "64. What a teacher does not say is as important as what a teacher does say.",
  "answer1": "A. False",
  "answer2": "B. True",
  "correctanswer": "A. False"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "65. Competitive activities have little value in establishing or maintaining an effective classroom climate and should thus be avoided.",
  "answer1": "A. False",
  "answer2": "B. True",
  "correctanswer": "A. False"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "66. Students feel important and are encouraged to participate in class when a teacher uses their ideas in moving a class lecture or activity forward.",
  "answer1": "A. False",
  "answer2": "B. True",
  "correctanswer": "B. True"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "67. The advancement in literacy, numeracy as well as Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics (STEM) fields is central to the Ministry of Education's vision of producing learners with strong experiential learning capabilities and backgrounds in career- focused programmes.",
  "answer1": "A. False",
  "answer2": "B. True",
  "correctanswer": "B. True"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "68. Strategies such as writing detailed test questions or prompts, including clear directions, and establishing and communicating clear grading criteria increase test reliability.",
  "answer1": "A. False",
  "answer2": "B. True",
  "correctanswer": "B. True"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "69. The standards-based curriculum was rolled out for the primary schools in Ghana in the academic year 2017\/2018.",
  "answer1": "A. False",
  "answer2": "B. True",
  "correctanswer": "A. False"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "70. Written assessments are activities in which the student selects or composes a response to a prompt.",
  "answer1": "A. False",
  "answer2": "B. True",
  "correctanswer": "B. True"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "71. The teacher cannot alter the classroom climate but should work for student success regardless Search for THE COMPANION GES PROMOTION EXAMS REVIEW on telegram and join of the climate.",
  "answer1": "A. False",
  "answer2": "B. True",
  "correctanswer": "A. False"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "72. The overall goal of the Ministry of Education is to provide relevant and quality education for disadvantaged Ghanaians.",
  "answer1": "A. False",
  "answer2": "B. True",
  "correctanswer": "A. False"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "73. The National Teaching Council is not the mandated body that oversees the posting of newly trained teachers in Ghana.",
  "answer1": "A. False",
  "answer2": "B. True",
  "correctanswer": "B. True"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "74. The skills that must be demonstrated in performance tasks cannot vary considerably.",
  "answer1": "A. False",
  "answer2": "B. True",
  "correctanswer": "A. False"
 },
 {
  "QUESTION": "75. In a school, teachers have many different types of assessment available to them.",
  "answer1": "A. False",
  "answer2": "B. True",
  "correctanswer": "B. True"
 }
]